翻译校对       Mam
日  听      HARERE
日听校对       Syura
翻译        阿里斯
时间轴       黑猫与牛奶
压制      娜夏
OP&ED       葉隠
Syura
诸神字幕组
Am I dreaming?
これは夢かな
ここは日本で　熱帯には属さないはずなんだけど
This is Japan.
There aren't supposed
to be any tropics here.
Look, Haruhi, there are birds
from the south tropics here.
ご覧ハルヒ　南国の鳥さんがいるよ
Pretty, aren't they? I wonder
what kind of birds they're called.
綺麗だね　何っていう鳥だろう
Where's the exit, again?
出口はどっちでしたっけ
Spending time taking it easy
like this is important for us
こういう他愛ない時間を過ごすのも
日夜美しさを磨く我々には大切なことなのだよ
to refine our round-the-clock beauty.
I don't care to spend time in such
pointless activities, so can I go?
無意味且つ果てしなくどうでもいいので帰っていいですか
I want to study,
勉強したいし　それに今日は洗濯しなくちゃならないんで
and I have to do my laundry today.
Where is this place, anyway?
だいたい　ここはどこなんですか
"A little earlier..."
"3:38pm"
"Ouran Academy, south building, front"
- Abduction...
...complete!
捕獲
完了
Huh? What the...
何
- All right, take her in.
- Roger!
よし　連行しろ
了解
Just a minute. No!
ちょっと　いやだあ
This is a theme park
that the Otori Group runs,
ここはうちの鳳グループが手がけているテーマパーク
熱帯アクアガーデンだよ
But Kyoya- senpai, didn't you say
that your family ran a hospital,
だって鏡夜先輩の家は病院とか
医療関係の仕事とか　言ってませんでした
or did some kind of
medical therapy work?
Well, it's a diversified enterprise,
that does lots of things,
まあ　多角経営ってやつで色々やってるが
ここはむしろ医療関連と言ってもいい
but you could say that
this is related to therapy.
There are many who suffer from stress,
or from feeling cooped-up,
ストレスや閉塞感に悩まされ
who would like to spend time
in the south tropics,
開放的な南国で休養したくても
but for economic reasons
or lack of time, are unable to go.
時間的　経済的な理由でできない人は大勢いる
This is a convalescent theme park,
to help treat those people.
ここはそんな人たちの療養にもなる癒し系テーマパークだよ
The Otori Group is always thinking
of the happiness of others.
わが鳳グループは　いつも人々の幸せを考えているんだ
This sounds relentlessly shady.
果てしなく胡散臭い
It doesn't open until next month,
オープンするのは来月からだが
but the Host Club has it reserved today
on a special advance invitation.
今日はホスト部貸切の特別先行招待さ
It feels so calm.
穏やかな気分だ
There aren't any guests here
that we have to serve, either.
今回だけはサービスしなければならないお客様もいない
It truly is a handsome
young warrior's holiday,
まさに美少年戦士の休息といったところか
I guess you could call it.
ハルちゃん
Haru-chan!
Want some coconut juice to drink?
Or maybe some mango cake?
ココナツジュース飲む　それともマンゴーケーキ食べる
えっと　じゃココナツジュースを
Um... sure, the coconut juice.
Okay!
Haruhi, let's go down the waterslide!
ハルヒ
ウォータースライダー行こうぜ
Then again, what's with the pullover?
つうかお前　そのパーカー姿は何
What, this...
これは…
"Women" "Men"
"Just a little earlier"
"4:02pm"
"In front of the changing room"
Okay, take care of her.
じゃ　この子よろしく
Very well.
かしこまりました
さ　藤岡様
Okay, Fujioka-sama. This way.
こちらへ
Just a minute!
ちょっと
"Changing room"
Just a minute! Just a minute!
ちょっと　ちょっと！
そちらの部屋に水着が用意してありますから
We have some swimsuits
available for you in this room.
We brought all of this year's latest,
that our mom designed.
うちの母がデザインした今年の新作　全部持ってきたから
You can choose whichever one you want.
好きなの選んでいいよ
Okay, Fujioka-sama, please select one.
さあ　藤岡様　お選びください
No, I don't need a swimsuit.
いや　いいです水着なんて
Well then, I will select one for you.
では　私が選ばせて頂きます
Hold on, not that one.
I don't want a bikini.
ちょっとそれは　ビキニとか嫌だ
But you'd look so good in this one...
こんなにお似合いですのに
Oh, look.
ほら　これなんかかわいいです
This one would be cute.
Eh? But that's nothing more
than strings, isn't it?
だってこれ　ただの紐でしょう
先輩
Senpai?
H-hurry up and put this on.
早くこれを着ろ
Girls should only show off
that much skin
女の子がお肌を見せていいのは
after they get married.
お嫁に行く時だけだ
So, you're not going swimming?
で　泳がないのか
By any chance, can you not swim?
もしかしたら金槌
I think I can swim
as well as the next guy,
人並みには泳げると思うけど
but I'm just not very
interested in this place,
こういうところ　あんまり興味ないし
and I'd rather just go home
than goof around here swimming.
泳いだりして遊ぶより
"Lazybones heroine"
早く帰りたいんだけど
What's so great about this
overblown facility, anyway?
だいたい何なんだろうこの大げさな設備は
A vinyl pool should be all you need
for playing in the water.
水遊びなんかビニールプールで十分でしょう
What's a vinyl pool?
ビニールプールって何
Let's see...
えっと　このくらいの大きさで
They're about this big,
ほら　空気入れて膨らませるやつだよ
and you pump them up full of air.
"Plastic Pool"
Dummy.
バーカ
That's called an air boat.
そりゃエアボートっていうの
"Inflatable Boat"
There's no way something
that small could be a pool.
そんな小さいのがプールなわけないだろう
Yeah.
It is a pool. Little kids
play in them a lot, you know?
プールだよ　よく小さい子が水遊びしてるでしょう
You idiots, Haruhi thinks it's a pool,
so let it be a pool.
"Whisper"
ハルヒがプールと思いこんでるんだからプールでいいんだ
Don't go embarrassing Haruhi.
ハルヒに恥をかかせるな
She only has a pitiful
commoner's knowledge.
庶民のいじらしい知恵なんだよ
Huh? But a boat is a boat.
だってボートはボートなのに
For some reason, I'm feeling
incredibly unpleasant.
なんというか　ものすごく不愉快なんですが
Never mind that, there's something
that's bothering me.
それより気になってたんだけどさ
Sir, why did you make Haruhi
wear that pullover?
殿はどうしてハルヒにこのパーカー着せたの
"Gulp!"
Ordinarily, you'd think...
普通に考えたらさ
I want to see Haruhi in a swimsuit!
ハルヒの水着姿が見たいんだよ
...would be the first thing you'd say.
って一番言いそうなのに
This is unexpected.
意外だよね
I can't imagine it's this,
まさかとは思うけど　あれっすか
but do you think it might be because
he doesn't want any punks besides himself
ハルヒの肌は自分以外の野郎には見せたくないとかそういうの
to see Haruhi's skin,
or something like that?
Oh, is that what this is?
ええ　そうなんだ
That would be quite
underhanded of him, huh?
そうってかなりのむっつりだよね
It'd be disgusting, all right.
気持ち悪いよね
Y-you idiots!
バ…バカもの
As her father, it's only natural,
being her guardian, that I would do so...
俺は父として　保護者として当然のことをだな
After all, even wearing a swimsuit,
大体　例え水着でも女の子は
it's not right for a girl to expose
her skin openly in front of boys.
男の前で無防備に肌を晒してはいかんのだ
Haru-chan!
ハルちゃん
Let's go play! They have
a current pool over there.
遊ぼう　あっちに流れるプールがあるよ
No, I'm not swimming today. Huh?
いいえ　今日は泳ぎません
あれ　ハニー先輩泳げないんですか
Honey- senpai, do you not know how to swim?
Just looks cuter this way.
だってこのほうがかわいいでしょう
兎柄だから
Because of the bunny design.
"I get it"
無邪気だね
Sweet and innocent.
ぬるい　ぬるいですわ
Tepid! Quite tepid!
"Powerful motor"
Renge-chan?
蓮華ちゃん
Is that rig set up everywhere?
この仕掛　どこにでもあるの
That's an amazing get-up.
すごい格好
What's that pattern on your belly?
そのお腹の模様は何
Oh, don't you know? I'm cosplaying.
あら　わかりませんの　コスプレですわ
Who are you?
何の
"La-la."
La-La? The manga magazine?
ララ　漫画雑誌か
A dream, risen from the abyss;
淵より出でし夢
those blue eyes,
lighting up young men's faces;
色
that tone of voice...
See? I'm Kisaragi Quon!
ほら　如月君
"Cosplay"
"The real thing"
We can't tell.
わかんない
We can't tell that at all.
それは全然わからんが
ほら殿　女の子があんな格好してるのに
Hey, sir, are you sure it's okay
for a girl to be dressed up...
...like that?
いいの
That might be okay.
あれは　いいんじゃないか
なんで
Why?
Maybe because it's cosplay?
コスプレだから　かな
In any case,
とにかく　皆さんは埴之塚先輩に対する認識がぬるいですわ
your understanding
of Haninozuka- senpai is lukewarm!
Takashi!
崇
Whee!
How do you mean?
どういうことだ
It's just like he got done saying.
先程おっしゃったでしょう
Just looks cuter this way.
だってこのほうがかわいいでしょう
I do not see that as being
sweet and innocent.
あれは無邪気などではないと見ました
Indeed it isn't.
確かに　文末に主語を入れるとわかる
Place a subject at the end
of the sentence, and you'll see.
Just looks cuter this way...
だってこのほうがかわいいでしょう
...don't I?
僕が
"I look cute!"
計算
He planned that!?
"He planned that?"
That's Haninozuka- senpai for you.
Apparently, he felt threatened
さすが埴之塚先輩
どうやら前回ショタ系の地位が脅かされたので
in his position as the little boy
type from last episode,
so he seems to be taking
steps to fortify himself.
強化策に出られているようですわね
見直しましたわ　なかなかディープ
I've got to give him more credit.
He is quite deep.
Look over here, everyone!
見て見てみんな
"Swimming briskly
against the current..."
Look! See? Even as hard
as we're swimming,
こんなに泳いでるのに同じ場所から全然進まないの
we never move forward
from the same place!
"Impossible to make out."
So, what's the deal?
だから何なのだ
Is that guy really that deep?
ディープなのか　あの人
Bulls-eye!
命中
Sir, let's play! Water gun battle!
殿　遊ぼうよ　ウォーターガンバトル
Me and Kaoru on a team against you, sir.
僕と馨チーム対殿ね
If you get it in the face, you lose,
and there's a penalty game.
顔に受けたら負けで　罰ゲーム
Hmph, who'd want to play along
with that childish game?
誰がそんな子供じみた遊びに付き合うか
Haruhi, let's get married right now.
ハルヒ　今すぐ結婚しよう
We'll have our honeymoon in Atami!
新婚旅行は熱海だ
"Pump!"
You think anyone is about
to let dear Haruhi marry you guys!?
かわいいハルヒを誰が貴様らなんざの嫁にやるか
お父さんは許さない
Daddy will not allow it!
"Swimming against the current pool"
"The 'l-can-do-it-by-myself' way"
Taking a break? Want something to drink?
休憩ですか　これ　飲みます
Yeah.
Take this!
くらえ　必殺　横飛ビーム
Surefire sideways-leaping beam!!
That's against the rules!
犯則犯則
- Honey- senpai!
- Mitsukuni!
ハニー先輩
光邦
Mori- senpai...
モリ先輩
Guys, we're going after Honey- senpai!
みんな　ハニー先輩を追いかけるぞ
This pool is the shortest way!
そっちのプールが近道だ
Charge!
突撃
Oh, that way is...
あ　そっちは
鰐が泳いでる
There are alligators swimming there!
Okay, that pool is out.
このプールはだめだ　こっちの道を行くぞ
Let's take this route!
They're here, too!
こっちも
And here, too!
Why are there alligators here?
なんで鰐が
There can't be.
ありえん
Those pools are the tropical animal area.
そちらのプールは熱帯動物エリアなんだが
I guess it is dangerous
to let the alligators run loose.
やはり鰐の放し飼いは危険か
Although, it's the current pool's
switch location that's the problem here.
ま　それより流水プールのスイッチの場所のほうが問題ありだな
I'll have to speak to the designers.
設計部に伝えておかねば
I have to thank you.
I've gotten some good data here.
礼を言うよ　いいデータが取れた
何の
For what!?
"Guinea pigs?"
This is Tropical Aqua Garden's area map.
これがこの熱帯アクアガーデンのエリアマップだ
This is our present location.
ここが我々のいる現在地
To get to this point, where I predict
Honey- senpai got carried away to,
そして恐らくハニー先輩が流されたと予測される
このポイントに行くには
we will need to go through the jungle
area in the southern block.
南ブロックの密林エリアを抜ける必要がある
That's a range of about 800 meters.
距離にして約８００メートル
There seem to be a lot
of indeterminate areas
なんかこの密林エリアって
in this jungle along our way.
途中あやふやなとこがいっぱいありますけど
Those are zones that
are still under development.
そこはまだ開発中のゾーンだ
There could be things in there
even more dangerous...
なんか鰐より危険な物とか
...than alligators.
いそうだよね
All right, this is a survival mission!
よし　これはサバイバル作戦だ
We have to safely penetrate
this jungle area,
我々はこの密林エリアを無事突破し
and rescue Honey- senpai!
ハニー先輩を救出しなければならない
This has all but become
a real jungle in here.
もうほとんど本物のジャングルだな
I've been hearing lots
of strange animal calls.
がいっぱいしてますけど
These animal voices...
...couldn't be the real thing, right?
まさか本物じゃないよね
I'm not too sure.
In all of the work we do,
どうだったかな
なんの仕事にせよ　うちは本物嗜好だからな
we tend to be authenticity-oriented.
As usual, Mori-senpai is poker- faced,
相変わらずモリ先輩は無表情で何考えてんのかわかんないけど
and I can't tell what he's thinking,
but though he may look calm,
it's times like these-
冷静に見えても　こういう時って
Mori- senpai...
モリ先輩が
...is acting about as
clumsy as you, sir.
まるで殿のようなドジを
What!?
何を
Sure enough, he's pretty concerned.
やっぱりかなり心配なんだな
Whoops, it must be squall time.
おっと　スコールタイムか
Mori- senpai is awfully close
to Honey- senpai, isn't he?
モリ先輩って　ハニー先輩とすごく仲いいですよね
Are they childhood friends, or something?
幼馴染とかですか
Those two...
あの二人は
...are cousins.
いとこだよ
Huh? They're relatives?
親戚だったんですか
The Morinozukas have been serving
銛之塚は代々埴之塚に仕えてきた家柄だよ
the Haninozuka family for generations.
"Haruhi's imagination"
Although, two generations ago,
they became relatives by marriage,
つっても二代前の婚姻で親戚になったわけだし
and the families' master-servant
relationship has long since faded away.
家の主従関係なんてとっくに風化してるはずなんだけど
Even so, Mori- senpai has always
accompanied Honey- senpai.
それでもモリ先輩はハニー先輩にいつも付き従ってんだよね
It must get his blood going.
やっぱり血が騒ぐんだろうな
The blood of the vassals of yore,
which flows through Mori- senpai.
モリ先輩の中に古から流れる家臣としての血が
What a great story! I'm touched!
いい話だ　感動
That's what you call a great story?
いい話なんですか　それって
I'm not sure I understand all this
about his blood getting going,
血が騒ぐっていうのはよくわかんないけど
but he does think an awful
lot of Honey- senpai, huh?
ハニー先輩のこと　すこぐ大切に思ってるんだな
モリ先輩　大丈夫ですよ　ハニー先輩は無事ですよ
Mori- senpai, it'll be all right.
Honey- senpai is safe.
He's tougher than you might think,
あれで意外と丈夫そうだし
and if he gets hungry, there are
a lot of bananas on the trees.
お腹が空いたらバナナもいっぱいなってますから
- Hey, now...
- How is he going to respond to that?
どんなフォローだよ
Yeah.
D-don't tell me Mori- senpai is out
for my spot as Haruhi's daddy, too!
まさかモリ先輩もハルヒのお父さんの座を
"Pit-a-pat..."
No, nobody is after that.
いや　だれも狙ってないから
Not that silly in-law position.
そんなバカな小姑ポジション
Who are you calling a silly in-law!?
だれがバカ小姑だ
Yeah,
あ　俺だ
- it's me
- Nyah! Silly in-law!
（バカ小姑）
いや　少々面倒な状況だね
- Oh, we've got a somewhat
troubling situation
- What did you call me!?
（何だと）
- Oh, we've got a somewhat
troubling situation
- Nyah! Silly in-law!
（バカ小姑）
Mori- senpai, it's not that way.
モリ先輩　そっちじゃないですよ
Honey- senpai is in the other direction.
ハニー先輩がいるのは反対側です
No, he's this way.
いや　こっちにいる
"Natural instinct"
Just a minute!
It's too dangerous to go alone!
ちょっと待って　一人じゃ危ないです
I'll come with you!
一緒に行きますから
Haruhi...
ハルヒ
That's the first time
he's ever called me by name.
初めて名前で呼ばれた
"A little bit pleased"
Yeah, okay, at once, please.
あ　それじゃ至急頼む
（バカ小姑　バカ小姑）
- Silly in-law! Silly in-law!
- Shut up!
（やかましい）
うちのプライベートポリスが捜索チームを出動させてくれるそうだ
- My family's private police force
is going to send in a search team.
- Silly in-law! Silly in-law!
- Shut up, I said!
（やかましいといってんだろう）
（バカ小姑　バカ小姑）
- They're better equipped
to find him than we are.
- Silly in-law! Silly in-law!
- Shut up!
俺たちが探すより的確だろう
（バカ小姑　バカ小姑）
ゲートに戻って待機を
- Let's go back to the gate and wait.
- Silly in-law! Silly in-law!
- Shut up!
（やかましい）
（バカ小姑　バカ小姑）
How many times are you
going to say it!?
（何で何度も言うの）
Hey, where are Mori- senpai and Haruhi?
おい　モリ先輩とハルヒは
"Tropical Aqua Garden
General Administration Headquarters"
"Otori Family Private Police"
緊急出動発令　緊急出動発令
Emergency mobilization order.
Kyoya-sama's friend has gone missing
near the current pool.
鏡夜様のご友人が流水プール付近より行方不明
Search target is a small young man.
捜索ターゲットは小柄な少年
Repeat, search target is a small young man.
繰り返す捜索ターゲットは小柄な少年である
なお　不審人物は容赦無くこれを排除せよ
Also, eliminate any suspicious
figures without mercy.
Eliminate any suspicious
不審人物は容赦無くこれを排除せよ
Target confirmed.
ターゲットを確認
"Small young man?"
"Suspicious figure?"
The target has been captured
by a suspicious man.
なお　ターゲットは不審な男に捕らわれている
Now taking subject into custody.
これより身柄を捕獲する
Now that I think about it,
そういえば　他の入場者については伝えてなかったな
I didn't tell them there
were any other visitors.
"Completely inadequate explanation"
ま　いいか
Oh, well.
You there! Let the boy go,
そこの男　その少年を離しなさい
or we will resort to using force!
さもなくば実力行使に出る
Oh, hold on!
ちょっと
The man is resisting!
Ready to fire warning shots!
この男　抵抗するぞ
威嚇射撃用意
Takashi, Haru-chan, move!
崇　ハルちゃん　退いて
What do you think you're
doing, pipsqueak!?
何をする　このチビ
構わん　こいつを
No matter, get this one, too!
Don't go being so reckless.
もう　無茶なことしないの
Picking on my friends is a no-no.
僕の仲間をいじめたら　めっだよ
"No-no!"
Haruhi!
ハルヒ　ハルヒ　無事か
Haruhi, are you all right!?
Ah, Tama-chan!
タマちゃん
- Huh?
- Honey- senpai!
ハニー先輩
Haruhi!
ハルヒ
I was worried about you.
心配したぞ
Not sure what happened here,
but they seem okay.
なんかわかんないけど　大丈夫みたいね
Well, Honey- senpai was the one
who did this, right?
だってこれハニー先輩がやったんだろう
Then he must have been holding back.
なら手加減してるって
え　それどういうことですか
Huh? What do you mean by that?
- Huh?
- You don't know?
お前知らないの
The Haninozukas have been famous
for their martial arts for generations.
埴之塚っていったら　代々武道の名門じゃんか
"Distinguished family"
They've instructed
not just the police and SDF,
警察や自衛隊だけじゃなく
but overseas military forces, as well.
海外の軍隊とかにも指導してんだぞ
In particular, Honey- senpai
特にハニー先輩は埴之塚始まって以来の猛者と言われ
has been called the dreadnaught
of the Haninozuka family,
for as long as it's been around,
and by the time he was in middle school,
すでに中等部の時に空手と柔道で全国制覇をしておられる
he was the national champion
in both karate and judo.
"Karate & judo champion"
Incidentally, Mori- senpai
also became the national champion
ちなみにモリ先輩も　中学の時　剣道で全国制覇しておられる
in kendo, when he was in middle school.
"National kendo champion"
Honey- senpai, what are you doing here?
ハニー先輩　何でここにいんの
You know what?
あのね　流れるプールのゴールに着いたから
I reached the end of the current pool,
so I went looking for everyone.
みんなを探してたの
We humbly apologize!
失礼をいたしました
I am a 2nd-generation student
of the Ishizuka Dojo!
自分は石塚道場の二代目です
I am a student of the Todoroki Dojo!
自分は等々力道場の門下生です
I'm from the Otake Dojo!
We are in your debt!
大滝道場の者です　お世話になっております
Oh, is that right?
あ　そうなの
Yes, sir! We're so sorry!
We were completely unaware
はは　恐れ入ります
まさか埴之塚光邦様とは露知らず
that we were looking
for Haninozuka Mitsukuni-sama,
and have committed a terrible offense!
大変な失礼をいたしました
Although, accidental though
it may have been,
しかし偶然とはいえ
my dojo will take pride in the day
that I was able to engage you,
光邦様に直接お手合わせ頂いたこの日は
Mitsukuni- sama, personally,
for generations to come!
我が道場末代までの誇りであります
"Deep"
He is deep. This goes way beyond deep.
ディープだ　余りにもディープすぎる
Takashi,
崇　ハルちゃんを守って偉かったね
you did very well protecting Haru-chan.
You didn't get lonesome
without me around, right?
僕がいなくても寂しくなかったね
I wouldn't say that.
そうでもなかった
We should go to the beach next,
to clear the mood.
今度は気分直しに海行こうぜ
いいね海
The beach would be nice.
You idiots, Haruhi wouldn't
be interested in that.
バーカ　ハルヒはそういうの興味ないって
I might not mind going to the beach.
海なら行ってもいいかも
This obviously artificial
location may not be any fun,
こういうあからさまな人工物は白けるんですけど
but the beach would be nice.
It's pretty there.
海はいいですよね　綺麗だし
よーし　わかった　次は海だ
All right, you got it!
Next, we go to the beach!
He said we're all going
to the beach next.
今度はみんなで海だって
That will be fun, huh?
楽しみだね
Yeah.
Why, after finally coming
all the way to the beach,
何でせっかく海にまで来て　俺とハルヒが喧嘩せねばならんのだ
do Haruhi and I have to get into a fight?
Senpai, I thought you weren't going
to talk to me anymore.
先輩　もう自分とは口を利かないんでしょう
Haruhi!
ハルヒ
Next time, " The Sun, the Sea,
and the Host Club"
Ouran High School Host Club will
be waiting for you, next week!
桜蘭高校ホストクラブ　来週も
お待ちしております